[{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify: (3<sup>n+3&nbsp;<\/sup>- 3<sup>n+2<\/sup>) \/ (3<sup>n+1&nbsp;<\/sup>-3<sup>n<\/sup>)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-9","9","10","-10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of p which satisfies the equation<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp;&radic;P - (6 \/&nbsp;&radic;P)&nbsp; = 1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4","-4","9","-9"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area of the circle&nbsp;4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 4y<sup>2<\/sup> - 400 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10\u03c0 sq. units","40\u03c0 sq. units","400\u03c0 sq. units","100\u03c0 sq. units"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Let the mean of x, y<sup>-1<\/sup>, z<sup>5<\/sup> be&nbsp; 6. Find the mean of 10,&nbsp;y<sup>-1<\/sup>, 12, x, z<sup>5<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["7","8","9","10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the addition of the y and x-intercepts of the line (2\/3)x + (3\/2)y + 9 = 0?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-19.5","19.5","20.5","-20.5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that h(x) = 3 + 2x&nbsp; and f(x) = 1 - x, find h(-f(x))<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1 - 2x","1 + 2x","2x - 1","-1 - 2x"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given that Cos \u03b1 = sin (90 -&nbsp;\u03b1), find y in terms of x&nbsp; in the equation&nbsp; ;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;Cos(1 + (x\/2)) = Sin(3y\/2)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["y = ((178 + x)\/3)","y = ((x - 178)\/3)","y = ((178 - x)\/3)","y = (-(178 + x)\/3)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>For What values of x is x<sup>-1<\/sup> &lt; -1?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0  < x < 1","x < -1, x > 0","x > 1, x < 0","-1 < x < 0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many ways can the letters of the word NWAFOR be permuted?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["7200","72","720","72000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the value of x&nbsp; for which x<sup>2<\/sup> - 5x + 6 is minimum?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5\/2","-5\/2","3","-3"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Integrate 5x<sup>4<\/sup> + e<sup>-x<\/sup> with respect to x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-e<sup>-x<\/sup> + x<sup>5<\/sup> + K","e<sup>-x<\/sup> + x<sup>5<\/sup> + K","-e<sup>-x<\/sup>- x<sup>5<\/sup> + K","-e<sup>-x<\/sup> + x<sup>4<\/sup> + K"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If X = {2,3,6,7,8} and Y = {6,7,10,3,17}, find Y - (X &cap; Y)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["{}","{10, 17}","{2,3,6,7,8,10,17}","{6,3,7}"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If&nbsp;&alpha; ,&nbsp;&beta; are the roots of equation 18 + 15x + 3x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0, find&nbsp;&alpha;&beta; -&nbsp;&alpha;-&nbsp;&beta;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","-11","10","-10"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the angle the line 1\/&radic;3y - x=0 makes with positive y- axis<\/strong><\/p>","options":["30<sup>o<\/sup>","60<sup>o<\/sup>","0<sup>o<\/sup>","45<sup>o<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the value of k in the equation 5\/2&radic;2 -&nbsp;&radic;8=k&radic;2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["4\/3","3\/4","-3\/4","-4\/3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate&nbsp;&int;<sup>1<\/sup><sub>o<\/sub>3xlog3dx<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","4","1","2"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>The probability of an event A given by P(A) is a number between&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-1 and 1","0 and 1\/2","0 and 1","-1 and 0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>Noting that sin<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8 + cos<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8 = 1,&nbsp; &nbsp;simplify&nbsp; 1-cos\u03b8 \/sin<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/1+cos\u03b8","1\/1-cos\u03b8","1\/1+sin\u03b8","1\/1-sin\u03b8"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>A circle has an eccentricity<\/strong><\/p>","options":["< 1","1",">1","0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If two element A and B are independent then P (A and B) is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(A\u22c2B","P(A\u222aB)","P(A)","P(B)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2015"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the probability of success in an even is y\/x, What is the possibility of failure?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x-y)\/y","(y-x)\/x","(x-y)\/x","(y-x)\/y"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the circumference of the circle x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> = (<sup>7<\/sup>\/<sub>\u03c0<\/sub>)<sup>2<\/sup>?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["16 units","14 units","15 units","13 units"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Resolve&nbsp;1\/x(1 + x) into partial fractions<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/x + 1\/(1+x)","1\/(1+x) - 1\/x","-1\/x - 1\/(1+x)","1\/x - 1\/(1+x)"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the equation 5<span style=\"font-size: 11.6667px;\"><sup>x<sup>2<\/sup><\/sup><\/span>&nbsp;= 25<span style=\"font-size: 11.6667px;\"><sup>x+4<\/sup><\/span><\/strong><\/p>","options":["-4, 2","-4, -2","4, -2","4, 2"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate&nbsp;\u2140<sup>2<\/sup><sub>n=1<\/sub> (2<sup>n<\/sup>&nbsp;+ 1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["28","31","29","32"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the line of intersection of the lines 3x - 2y = 5, 2x + 5y = -7<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x = <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub> , y = - <sup>31<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub>","x = - <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub> , y = <sup>31<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub>","x = - <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub> , y = - <sup>31<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub>","x = <sup>11<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub> , y =  <sup>31<\/sup>\/<sub>19<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve 4x<sup>2<\/sup> + 20x - 24 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1,6","-1,-6","6,-1","-6,1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the 15th term of the sequence -3, 2, 7, . . .?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["65","66","68","67"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><b>Evaluate <sup>(log\u221a27 log\u221a8)<\/sup>\/<sub>log3 - log2<\/sub><\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","-<sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub>","<sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>","- <sup>3<\/sup>\/<sub>2<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Integrate 4x<sup>3<\/sup> + 1\/x with respect to x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["lnx + x<sup>4<\/sup> + K","x<sup>-1<\/sup> + x<sup>4<\/sup> + K","12x<sup>2<\/sup> + x<sup>-2<\/sup> + K","(1\/5)xx<sup>5<\/sup> + x<sup>-2<\/sup> + K"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the Diameter of the circle 2x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2y<sup>2<\/sup> - 50 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["- 10 units","10 units","25 units","- 25 units"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the coordinate of the center of the circle x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x - 4y = 10?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(-1, -2)","(1, 2)","(-1, 2)","(1, -2)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Simplify log<\/strong><strong>xx<sup>4<\/sup> + log&nbsp;<sub>x<\/sub>4<sup>x<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["4x","4\/x","4 + x","4x<sub>4x<\/sub><sup>4x<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given <em>f(x) =&nbsp;<\/em>3 + x and&nbsp;<em>g(x) =&nbsp;<\/em>3-x, find&nbsp;<em>g(f(x)) = 3 -&nbsp;f(x)<\/em><\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","x","-x","0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the remainder when x<sup>3<\/sup> + 5x<sup>2<\/sup> -6x + 1 is divided by x-1?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-1","2","-2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If &alpha; and &beta; are the root of equation 6 + 5x - x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0, find&nbsp;&beta;<\/strong><strong>&beta; + &beta; +&nbsp;&beta;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","-11","1","-1"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2013"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the universal set U = {1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10}, M =(1,3,5,7,9) and N = (2,4,6,8,10) which of the following is equal to (M U N)'?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(M  n N)'","M'UN'","M' n N'","M n N"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Cos (180 -&nbsp;\u03f4) is equivalent to which of the following?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["cos (\u03f4 - 180)","cos\u03f4","-cos\u03f4","-cos(180 + \u03f4)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the circle with center (-1, 3) and radius 4.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> - 6x + 2y = 6","x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x - 6y = 16","x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> - 6x + 2y = 16","x<sup>2<\/sup> + y<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x - 6y = 6"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find&nbsp;<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">dy&nbsp;<\/span> , if y = <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">3<\/span>&nbsp; &nbsp;&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;dx&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;&radic;x<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["-3\/2x<sup>-3\/2<\/sup>","3x<sup>-3\/2<sup>","3\/2x<sup>-3\/2<\/sup>","3\/4x<sup>-3\/2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Integrate&nbsp; <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">1&nbsp;<\/span><\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;2x<\/strong><\/p>","options":["Not defined","0","1\/2Inx + C","1\/4<sup>x<\/sup><sup>2<\/> + C"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>If the mean of the numbers a,b,c,d,e is x, find the mean of numbers a + k,b + 2k,c - k,d - 2k,e.&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x","x + k","x - k","2x"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Factorize: a<sup>2<\/sup>-b<sup>2<\/sup> + (a+b)<sup>2<\/sup><\/strong><\/p>","options":["2a<sup>2<\/sup>","2a (a-b)","2a (a+b)","2b (b-a)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Let&nbsp;&alpha;&nbsp;and &beta; be roots of quadratic equation x<sup>2<\/sup> + 2x - 3 = 0.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Then &alpha;&beta; is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3","-2","2","6"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Convert 69<sub>10 <\/sub>to a number in base two<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1001101","10100001","1000101","100101"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>The speed of 3o kilometres per minute, expresssed in centimeters per second is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["5","50","5000","50000"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate x if log<sub>4<\/sub> (x+3) (x-3) = 2.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3 or -3","5 or -5","5 or -3","3 or -5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2011"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find x if x<sup>2&nbsp;<\/sup><\/strong>-&nbsp;<strong>2x - 15 = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3, -5","-3, 5","1, 15","-2, -15"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>A father leaves a legacy of N45 million for his children - Peter, David and Paul - to be shared in the ratio 7:5:3. What amount in million Naira would each receive respectively?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N14, N7, N3","N15, N5, N3","N21, N15, N9","N20, N16, N10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>As \u0278 tends to zero, what does cos&theta; tend to?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["sin\u03b8","0","1\/2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve the equation to determine the value of&nbsp;<\/strong><span style=\"font-weight: bolder; font-size: 0.875rem;\">\u03b8 ;<\/span><strong style=\"font-size: 0.875rem;\">&nbsp;&nbsp;2cos\u03b8 + sin<sup>2<\/sup>\u03b8 - 2 = 0.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","2","4","0"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>if tanx = <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">sinx,<\/span> find tan(90&deg; + x) for acute value of x.<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;cosx<\/strong><\/p>","options":["- cot x","- tan x","cot x","tan x"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>The indefinite integral of xe<sup>x<\/sup>, for any real constant c is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["c","x + e<sup>x<\/sup> + c","x<sup>2<\/sup> + e<sup>x<\/sup> + c","e<sup>x<\/sup>(x - 1) + c"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the area under the curve y(x) = sin x between x = 0 and x =&nbsp;&pi;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","1","-2","\u03c0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a convex polygon with n sides, the sum of interior angles is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(n - 2)\u03c0","2(n - 1)\u03c0","4(n - 1)\u03c0","(2n - 4)\u03c0"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the equation of the line perpendicular to the line y = 2x + 1 and passing through a point (3, 1).<\/strong><\/p>","options":["y = 1\/2x + 5\/2","y = -1\/2x + 5\/2","y = x + 5","2y = x + 5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>What is the distance between points (1,2) and (4,5) on a plane?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\u221a2","2\u221a3","3","9"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Integrate&nbsp;&int; 2tan (2x +&nbsp;&pi;)dx<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2cos(2x + \u03c0) + k","log (cos(2x + \u03c0) + k","-log(cos(2x + \u03c0) + k","4cot(2x + \u03c0) + k"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the values of x for which 5 + 2x - 3x<sup>2<\/sup> = 0<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-2 and 6\/5","-1 and 5\/3","-2 and -1","6\/5 and 5\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>If (<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">3<\/span>)<sup>x<\/sup> (<span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">2<\/span>)<sup>y<\/sup> = <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">32<\/span>, find the value of 3y - 2x&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;4&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 3&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 27<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-1","7","1","-7"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2010"},{"question":"<p><strong>Factorize 6x<sup>2<\/sup> - 14x - 12<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2(x + 3)(3x - 2)","6(x - 2)(x + 1)","2(x - 3)(3x - 2)","6(x + 2)(x-1)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><b>What is the product of <sup>27<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub> - (3)<sup>-3<\/sup> and (<sup>1<\/sup>\/<sub>5<\/sub>)<\/b><\/p>","options":["5","3","2","1"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>if the lenght of the sides of a right angled triangle are (3x + 1)cm, (3x - 1)cm and xcm, what is x?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","6","18","12"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>in 1984, Tolu was 24 years old and his father was 45 years. In what year was Tolu exactly half his father`s age?&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1982","1981","1983","1979"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the probability that a number selected at random 40 - 50 is a prime<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/11","5\/11","5\/10","4\/10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A man kept 6 black, 5 brown and 7 purple shirts in a drawer. What is the probability of his picking a purple sihrt with his eyes&nbsp; closed<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/7","7\/18","11\/18","7\/11"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>An (n - 2)<sup>2<\/sup> sided figure has n diagonals, find the number n of diagonals for a 25 sided figure<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8","7","6","9"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the probability of selecting a figure which is parallelogram from a square, a rectangle, a rhombus, a kite and a trapezium<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3\/5","2\/5","4\/5","1\/5"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If P varies inversely as V and V varies directly as R<sup>2<\/sup>, find the relationship between P and R given that R = 7 when P = 2<\/strong><\/p>","options":["p = 98R<sup>2<\/sup>","PR<sup>2<\/sup> = 98","p<sup>2<\/sup>R = 89","P = 1\/98R"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>if 7 and 189 are the first and fourth terms of a geometric progression respectively, find the sum for the first three terms of the progression<\/strong><\/p>","options":["182","180","91","63"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find the positive number<i>n <\/i>such that thrice its square is equal to twelve times the number<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1","4","2","5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sector of a circle radius 7.2cm which subtends an angle 300&deg; at the centre is used to form a cone. What is the radius of the base the cone?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6cm","7cm","8cm","9cm"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>if pq + 1 = q<sup>2<\/sup> and t = 1\/p - 1\/pq express t in terms of q<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/pq","1\/q+1","1\/p+1","1\/1-q"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Given a regular hexagon, calculate each interior angle of the hexagon&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["60\u00b0","30\u00b0","120\u00b0","15\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>Find n if log<sub>2<\/sub>4 + log<sup>7<\/sup><sub>2<\/sub> log<sub>2<\/sub>n=-1<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","14","12","27"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x = 1 is root of the equation x<sup>3<\/sup>-2x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x+6, find the other roots.<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3 and 2","2 and 2","3 and -2","1 and 3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>The value of (0.303)<sup>3<\/sup> - (0.02)<sup>3<\/sup> is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.019","0.0019","0.00019","0.02781"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>List all integers satisfying the inequality -2&lt;2x-6&lt;4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2,3,4,5","2,3,4","2,5","3,4"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>If 3<sup>2y<\/sup>&nbsp;- 6(3<sup>y<\/sup>) = 27, find y<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","1","2","-3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A number of pencils were shared out among Peter, Paul and Audu in the ratio 2:3:5 respectively. If Peter got 5, how many were share ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15","25","30","50"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><strong>A sum of money was invested at 8% per annum simple interest. If after 4 years, the money became <span style=\"text-decoration: line-through;\">N<\/span>330.00, what is the amount originally invested<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N180","N165","N150","N250"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2009"},{"question":"<p><b>The expression a<sup>3<\/sup>+ b<sup>3<\/sup> is equal to<\/b><\/p>","options":["(a<sup>2<\/sup> + b)(a-ab+b<sup>2<\/sup>)","(a+b)(a<sup>2<\/sup>-ab+b<sup>2<\/sup>)","(a-b<sup>2<\/sup>)(a<sup>2<\/sup>-ab+b)","(a-b)(a<sup>2<\/sup>+ab+b<sup>2<\/sup>)"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><b>Factorize 16(3x + 2y)<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 25(a + 2b)<sup>2<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["(12x + 8y + 5a + 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","(12x + 8y - 5a - 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","20(3x + 2y - a - 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)","20(3x + 2y + a + 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cylinder has height 4cm and base radius 5cm , its volume to 3 significant figure is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["314.2cm<sup>3<\/sup>","31.42cm<sup>3<\/sup>","251.4cm<sup>3<\/sup>","251cm<sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Let 3logx+logy = 3, then y is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(x\/10) <sup>3<\/sup>","(x\/10) <sup>-3<\/sup>","(10\/x) <sup>-1\/3<\/sup>","(10\/x) <sup>3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>If&nbsp; &nbsp;10<sup>2<\/sup>\/a<sup>2<\/sup> - y<sup>2<\/sup>\/b<sup>2<\/sup> = 1, then y is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["+\/- b\/a\u221aa<sup>2<\/sup>-x<sup>2<\/sup>","+\/- b\/a\u221a10<sup>2<\/sup>-a<sup>2<\/sup>","a\/b\u221aa<sup>2<\/sup>-x<sup>2<\/sup>","+\/-a\/b\u221ax<sup>2<\/sup>-a<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>The expression a<em>x<\/em><sup>2<\/sup>+ b<em>x&nbsp;<\/em> takes the value 6 when x = 1 and 10 when&nbsp;<em>x<\/em> = 2. Find its value when&nbsp;<em>x<\/em> = 5<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","12","6","-10"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>Dividing 2x<sup>3<\/sup>-3x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x + 1 by x + 3 gives the remainder<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-3","47","61","-47"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2008"},{"question":"<p><strong>All the vertices of an isosceles triangle lie on a circle and each of the base angles of the triangle is 65\u00b0. The angle subtended at the center of the circle by the base of the triangle is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["130\u00b0","115\u00b0","100\u00b0","65\u00b0"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A square tile measure 20cm by 20cm. How many of such tiles will cover a floor measuring 5m by 4m?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["500","400","320","250"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The volume of a certain sphere is numerically equal to twice its surface area. The diameter of this sphere is :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["6","9","12","\u221a6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bearing of 310&deg;, expressed as a compass bearing is :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["N50\u00b0W","N40\u00b0W","S40\u00b0W","S50\u00b0W"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Which of the following specified sets of data is <span style=\"text-decoration: underline;\">not nessarily<\/span> sufficient for the construction of a triangle ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["three angles","two sides and a right angle","two sides and an inclined angle","three sides"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The average age of the three children in a family is 9years. If the average age of their parent is 39years, the average age of the whole family is :<\/strong><\/p>","options":["20years","21years","24years","27years"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><b>Simplyfy 1 + <sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> - 3 \u00f7 (1 + <sup>2<\/sup>\/<sub>3<\/sub> of <sup>6<\/sup>\/<sub>7<\/sub>)<\/b><\/p>","options":["<sup>-8<\/sup>\/<sub>33<\/sub>","<sup>21<\/sup>\/<sub>11<\/sub>","<sup>33<\/sup>\/<sub>21<\/sub>","<sup>-21<\/sup>\/<sub>8<\/sub>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate x in base 3 if 41<sub>x<\/sub> - 22<sub>x<\/sub> = 17<sub>x<\/sub><\/strong><\/p>","options":["11","8","12","22"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>When the price of egg was raised by #2 an egg, the numbers of eggs which can be bought for #120 is reduced by 5 .The present price of an egg is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["#6","#7","#8","#10"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>How long will it take a sum of money invested at 8% simple intrest to double the original sum?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["8years","10.5years","12years","12.5years"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The journey from Lagos to Ibadan usually takes a motorist 1 hour 30 minutes. By increasing his average speed by 20km\/hr, the motorist saves 15 minutes. His usual speed, in km\/hr&nbsp; is ?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["100","90","85","80"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x = 0.0012 + 0.00074 + 0.003174, what is the difference between x to 2 decimal places and x to 1 significant figure?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.01","0.0051","0.1","0.005"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The angle of depression of two points A and B on a plane&nbsp; field from the top of a mast erected between A and B are 30<sup>0<\/sup> and 45<sup>0<\/sup> respectively. If A is wesward of B, find \/AB\/ if the height of the mast is 15m from the field<\/strong><\/p>","options":["15\u221a3m","5(3+\u221a3m","15(1+\u221a3","15(\u221a3-1)"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>The radius of a circle is given as 10cm subject to an error of 0.2cm. The error in the area of the circle is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["1\/4%","1\/50%","2%","4%"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>If&nbsp;\u03b8 is acute, evaluate&nbsp; [cos(90 -&nbsp;\u03b8)+sin(180-\u03b8)]\/[cos(180-\u03b8)-sin(90-\u03b8)]<\/strong><\/p>","options":["tan\u03b8","-tan\u03b8","cot\u03b8","-cot\u03b8"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a survey of 100 students in an institution, 80 students speak Yoruba, 22 speak Igbo, while 6 speak neither Igbo nor Yoruba. How many students speak Yoruba and Igbo<\/strong><\/p>","options":["96","8","64","12"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains 5 yellow balls, 6 green balls and 9 black balls. A ball is drawn from the bag. What is the probability that it is black or yellow ball<\/strong><\/p>","options":["37\/160","133\/400","7\/10","233\/180"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Weight(kg)&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;60-62&nbsp; &nbsp; 63-65&nbsp; &nbsp; 66-68&nbsp; &nbsp; 69-71&nbsp; &nbsp; 72-74<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;F&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;5&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 18&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;42&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 27&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 8<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Calculate the mean of the distribution to two decimal places<\/strong><\/p>","options":["64.45","62.45","67.45","65.45"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Weight(kg)&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;60-62&nbsp; &nbsp; 63-65&nbsp; &nbsp; 66-68&nbsp; &nbsp; 69-71&nbsp; &nbsp; 72-74<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;F&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;5&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 18&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;42&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 27&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp; 8<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>Calculate the mode of the distribution to two decimal places<\/strong><\/p>","options":["67.35","65.33","65.53","67.53"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2007"},{"question":"<p><strong>Solve for p in the following equation given in base two 11(P + 110) = 1001P<\/strong><\/p>","options":["10","110","11","111"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><b>Factorize 16(3x + 2y)<sup>2<\/sup> \u2013 25(a + 2b)<sup>2<\/sup><\/b><\/p>","options":["(12x + 8y + 5a + 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","(12x + 8y - 5a - 10b) (12x + 8y - 5a - 10b)","20(3x + 2y - a - 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)","20(3x + 2y + a + 2b) (3x + 2y + a + 2b)"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Let log y + log 3 = 3. Then y is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["(10\/x)<sup>3<\/sup>","(x\/10)<sup>3<\/sup>","(x\/10)<sup>-3<\/sup>","(10\/x)<sup>-1\/3<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>If x<sup>2<\/sup>\/a<sup>2 <\/sup>&ndash; y<sup>2<\/sup>\/b<sup>2 <\/sup>= 1, then y is <\/strong><\/p>","options":["&#177; b\/a &#8730;x<sup>2<\/sup>-a<sup>2<\/sup>","a\/b &#8730;a<sup>2<\/sup>-x<sup>2<\/sup>","&#177; a\/b &#8730;x<sup>2<\/sup>-a<sup>2<\/sup>","&#177; b\/a &#8730;a<sup>2<\/sup>-x<sup>2<\/sup>"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A cyclist rode for 30 minutes at X km\/hr, if the total distance covered is less than 60km, what is the range of values for X?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["X < 14","X < 20","X < 29","X < 28"],"answerIndex":4,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A business invested a total of&nbsp;\u20a6 200,000 in two compaines which paid dividends of 5% and 7% respeectively. If he received a total of&nbsp;\u20a611,600 as dividends, how much did he ivest at 5% <\/strong><\/p>","options":["\u20a6160,000","\u20a6140,000","\u20a6120,000","\u20a680,000"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In a class, 37 students take at least one of Chemistry, Economics and Government, 8 students take Chemistry, 19 takes Economics and 25 take Government. 12 students take Economics and Government but nobody take Chemistry and Economics. How many students take both Chemistry and Government?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["3","4","5","6"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Z is partially constant and partly varies inversely as the square of d, when d = 1, z = 11 and when d = 2, z = 5. Find the value of z when d = 4<\/strong><\/p>","options":["2","3","5","5.5"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Expand the expression (x<sup>2<\/sup>-2x-3)(x<sup>2<\/sup>+x+1)<\/strong><\/p>","options":["x<sup>4<\/sup>-4x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x-3","-x<sup>3<\/sup>-4x<sup>2<\/sup>+5x-3","x<sup>4<\/sup>-x<sup>3<\/sup>-4x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x-3","x<sup>4<\/sup>-4x<sup>2<\/sup>-5x-3"],"answerIndex":3,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>The indefinite integral of the function f(x) = x cosx for any constant k, is<\/strong><\/p>","options":["-xcosx + sinx + k","xsinx-cosx","xsinx + cosx + k","x + sin x + cos x"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>Evaluate the integral &int;<sup>2<\/sup><sub>1<\/sub>(x<sup>2<\/sup> + 3\/x)dx&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p>&nbsp;<\/p>","options":["8\/3 + ln2","7\/3 + ln2","7\/3 - ln3","8\/3"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>A bag contains 10 balls of which 3 are red and 7 are white. Two balls are drawn at random. Find the probability of none the balls is red, if the draw is&nbsp;<\/strong><\/p>\r\n<p><strong>With replacement<\/strong><\/p>","options":["0.49","1","0.47","0.21"],"answerIndex":1,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>How many different three digit numbers can be formed using the integers 1 to 6 if no integer occurs twice in a number?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["720","1260","2520","5040"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"},{"question":"<p><strong>In how many different ways can be letters of the word GEOLOGY be arranged in order?<\/strong><\/p>","options":["720","1260","2520","5040"],"answerIndex":2,"examYear":"2006"}]